William Remsen Strickland Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
William Remsen Strickland Collection 1926-1991 (bulk 1946-1970)
ML31.S77
Strickland, William
8600 items 39 containers 16 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
This collection is comprised of materials related to the distinguished career of American conductor and composer William Remsen Strickland (1914-1991). It includes correspondence, concert programs, publicity materials, newspaper and magazine clippings, music manuscripts by Strickland and other composers, articles, speeches and notes, photographs, scrapbooks, datebooks, journals, and recordings.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981--Correspondence.; Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981.; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935.; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935.; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965--Correspondence.; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965.; Effinger, Cecil, 1914-1990--Correspondence.; Howe, Mary, 1882-1964--Correspondence.; Hull, Anne--Correspondence.; Ives, Charles, 1874-1954.; Keller, Homer, 1915-1996--Correspondence.; Kennan, Kent Wheeler, 1913-2003--Correspondence.; Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991--Correspondence.; Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007--Correspondence.; Pleasants, Henry--Correspondence.; Pleasants, Virginia--Correspondence.; Rorem, Ned, 1923- --Correspondence.; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951--Correspondence.; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951.; Sowerby, Leo, 1895-1968--Correspondence.; Strickland, William--Correspondence.; Strickland, William--Portraits.; Strickland, William.; Strickland, William.; Thorne, Francis--Correspondence.; Ward, Robert, 1917- --Correspondence.
Organizations
Dumbarton Oaks Chamber Orchestra.; Impuriaru Firuhāmonikku Kōkyōgakudan (Japan); Nashville Symphony Orchestra.; Nihon Firuhāmonī Kōkyō Gakudan.; Oratorio Society of New York.; Sinfóniúhljómsveit íslands.
Subjects
Conductors (Music)--United States--Correspondence.
Form/Genre
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Programs.; Scrapbooks.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The Library of Congress received a small quantity of music manuscripts and correspondence as a deposit from William Remsen Strickland in November 1967. Additional collection materials were received throughout 1968 and a formal agreement of deposit was signed in February 1969. These materials were later converted to a gift following Strickland's death in 1991.
Transfers
Sound recordings have been transferred to the Library of Congress, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division.
Related Material
The collection contained a small amount of audio tape reels and cassettes of Strickland's live performances and personal interviews from the 1940s and 1950s. Unique items include his electronic realizations of Ives’ The Unanswered Question and Central Park in the Dark, as well as a [1945?] recording of Samuel Barber playing selections from his ballet Medea at the piano. A complete list of this material is located in the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress.
Access and Restrictions
The William Remsen Strickland Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use. Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
William Remsen Strickland was born in Defiance, Ohio, in 1914. After beginning his musical career as an organist, he shifted his focus to conducting. He served in the U.S. Army from 1941-1946, attending the Army music school and subsequently founding the Army Music School Choir, whose performances featured compositions by musicians serving in the armed forces, including Cecil Effinger, Homer Keller, and Kent Kennan. Upon exiting the Army in 1946, Strickland co-founded the Nashville Symphony Orchestra, which he led until 1951. He also conducted several concerts and recordings of modern music at Dumbarton Oaks, including the first recording of his friend Samuel Barber's Knoxville: Summer of 1915 with Eleanor Steber.
In 1952 and 1953, Strickland traveled to Vienna on a Fulbright scholarship to begin his life-long campaign of championing the works of American composers abroad. For nearly three years, Strickland led the Vienna Symphony in performances of works by Samuel Barber, Aaron Copland, Henry Cowell, Mary Howe, Edward MacDowell, Robert Ward, and others. From 1955 to 1959, Strickland was the musical director of the New York Oratorio Society, which he led in performances of Stravinsky, Honegger, Barber, and Cowell, in addition to the group's annual Christmas concerts of Handel's Messiah. Under the auspices of the U.S. State Department, he continued his efforts to promote American music, traveling to Japan, the Philippines, Korea, and Vietnam in 1958 and 1959. In addition to working with local orchestras to perform concerts, Strickland made numerous recordings of contemporary compositions for the record label Composers Recordings, Inc. (CRI).
Strickland returned to Europe in 1963, conducting performances and recordings in Finland, Poland, and Sweden, as well as directing the Iceland Symphony Orchestra from 1962-63. In the late 1960s, he established a residence in Portugal and turned his attention to his study of the music of Charles Ives, whom he had long considered the quintessential American composer. A planned book on Ives never came to fruition, and Strickland instead focused on creating electronic realizations of several Ives compositions, which he felt were impossible to perform as the composer intended. After retiring to Connecticut, Strickland continued his experiments with electronic music, recording in 1979 An Electronic Visit to the Zoo and Sound Hypnosis. He died in 1991.
Scope and Content Note
The William Remsen Strickland Collection spans the period 1926-1991; the bulk of the materials date from 1946-1970. The collection includes correspondence, concert programs, publicity materials, newspaper and magazine clippings, music manuscripts, printed scores, articles, speeches and notes, photographs, scrapbooks, datebooks, journals, graphs, and recordings.
Organization of the William Remsen Strickland Collection
The William Remsen Strickland Collection is organized into ten series:
Regional Files
Correspondence
Music
Writings
Journals
Datebooks
Photographs
Posters
Scrapbooks
Miscellaneous
http://lccn.loc.gov/2009536077
Container List
- Regional Files (Box 1-7)
  The "Regional files" series documents Strickland’s travels throughout his career, beginning with his service in the U.S. Army. In many cases, Strickland remained in a given region for a period ranging from several months to several years. The series is arranged chronologically, with each major region divided into four distinct sub-series: correspondence (related directly to each region), concert programs, publicity materials (advertisements, newspaper and magazine clippings), and miscellaneous documents. Many of the foreign language clippings are supplemented with translations provided by the U.S. State Department.
  - U.S. Army, 1941-1946 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 1/1)
      - 1942-1945 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Programs (Box-folder 1/2)
      - 1942-1944 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Clippings, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/4-5)
      - U.S. Army records (Box-folder 1/4)
      - U.S. Army personnel documents (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Nashville, 1946-1951 (Box 1-2)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 1/6-13)
      - Marjorie Cooney (manager of NSO) to WRS (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Walter and Huldah Sharp to WRS, 1945-1951 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - WRS to Walter Sharp, 1945-1950 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Re: death of Walter Sharp, 1970 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Letters and telegrams to WRS re: 1949 Jan. 15 broadcast of NSO on NBC (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Miscellaneous to WRS, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 1/11)
      - Miscellaneous to WRS, 1951-1968 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - Miscellaneous to WRS, undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Programs (Box-folder 2/1-4)
      - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 2/1)
      - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - 1948-1951 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - 1986-1988 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 2/5)
      - 1949-1987 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/6-9)
      - NSO business documents (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Pre-NSO orchestra plans (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Notes by WRS (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Letters of recommendation for WRS (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Vienna, 1951-1955 (Box 2-3)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 2/10-3/2)
      - Re: Fulbright scholarships (Box-folder 2/10)
      - Re: recordings (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Programs (Box-folder 3/3)
      - 1952-1955 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 3/4)
      - 1952-1955 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Planning documents (Box-folder 3/5)
  - New York Oratorio Society, 1955-1959 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 3/6-10)
      - Chorus members to WRS (Box-folder 3/6)
      - Letters to WRS (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Letters to WRS, undated (Box-folder 3/8)
      - Telegrams to WRS (Box-folder 3/9)
      - Letters by WRS (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Programs (Box-folder 3/11)
      - 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 3/12-13)
      - 1955-1957 (Box-folder 3/12)
      - Clippings,1955-1957 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Japan (Box 3-4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 3/14-17)
      - U.S. State Department (Box-folder 3/14)
      - Tokyo (Box-folder 3/15)
      - Osaka (Box-folder 3/16)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Programs (Box-folder 4/1-2)
      - Tokyo (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Osaka (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 4/3-7)
      - Tokyo (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Tokyo clippings (Box-folder 4/4-5)
      - Osaka (Box-folder 4/6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/8)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Philippines (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 4/9-13)
      - 1957-1966 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Programs (Box-folder 4/10)
      - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 4/11-12)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 4/11-12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/13)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Korea (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 5/1)
      - 1958-1961 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Programs (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Undated (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 5/4)
      - Undated (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Vietnam (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 5/5)
      - 1959-1967 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Programs (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Saigon (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 5/7)
      - Saigon (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 5/8)
      - Saigon (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Iceland (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 5/9)
      - 1961-1963 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Programs (Box-folder 5/10)
      - 1962-1964 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 5/11)
      - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 5/12)
      - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Finland (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 6/1)
      - 1962-1964 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Programs (Box-folder 6/2)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 6/3-4)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 6/3-4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 6/5)
      - 1964, undated (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Poland (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 6/6)
      - 1964-1970 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Programs (Box-folder 6/7)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 6/8)
      - Undated (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 6/9-10)
      - Contracts (Box-folder 6/9)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Miscellaneous U.S. performances and recordings (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Programs (Box-folder 7/2-3)
      - 1942-1963 (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Music at Dumbarton Oaks: A record, 1940-1970; Dumbarton Oaks, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 7/4)
      - 1956-1967 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Miscellaneous non-U.S. performances and recordings (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 7/5-6)
      - Sweden (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Programs (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 7/8)
      - 1962-1968 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/9-13)
      - U.S. State Department grant documents (Box-folder 7/9)
      - U.S. State Department Regional voucher (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Awards and honors (Box-folder 7/11)
      - Publicity re: H.W. Gray Publishing (Box-folder 7/12)
      - Publicity re: miscellaneous recordings (Box-folder 7/13)
- Correspondence (Box 8-14)
  The "Correspondence" series is divided into three sub-series: letters and telegrams received by Strickland, those written by Strickland, and miscellaneous documents. The latter includes material related to Strickland’s recordings, interviews with researchers, potential employers throughout his career, letters between other parties that reference Strickland, and letters written to the H.W. Gray Publishing Co. Substantial correspondence is present from composers Samuel Barber, Henry Cowell, Cecil Effinger, Mary Howe, Homer Keller, Ned Rorem, Arnold Schoenberg, and Robert Ward. Other notable correspondents include Henry and Ginny Pleasants, as well as Strickland’s close friends Anne Hull, Margaret F. Castle, Louise Davis, and Sidney and Eleanor Clark.
  - Letters to WRS (Box 8-11)
    - Antheil, George (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Avshalomov, Jacob (Box-folder 8/2)
    - A- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Bacon, Ernst (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Barber, Samuel (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Beach, Amy Marcy Cheney (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Beeson, Jack (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Berg, Helene (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Berger, Karen (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Berger, Theodore (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Bergsma, William (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Berkeley, Lenox (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Biggs, E. Power (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Bingham, Seth (Box-folder 8/14)
    - Bliss, Arthur (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Britten, Benjamin (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Britton, Dorothy (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Brunold, Hella (Box-folder 8/18)
    - Buell, William (Box-folder 8/19)
    - B- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Carlson, Larry (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Carpenter, John Alden (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Cary, Tristam (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Castle, Margaret F. (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Chanler, Theodore (Box-folder 8/26)
    - Chávez, Carlos (Box-folder 8/27)
    - Citkowitz, Israel (Box-folder 8/28)
    - Claflin, Avery (Box-folder 8/29)
    - Copland, Aaaron (Box-folder 8/30)
    - Cowell, Henry (Box-folder 8/31)
    - Cowell, Olive (Box-folder 8/32)
    - Cowell, Sidney (Box-folder 8/33)
    - Creston, Paul (Box-folder 8/34)
    - Crofts, Margaret Lee (Box-folder 8/35)
    - Curzon, Clifford (Box-folder 8/36)
    - C- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 8/37)
    - Daniel, Oliver (Box-folder 8/38)
    - Davis, Louise (Box-folder 8/39)
    - Diamond, David (Box-folder 8/40)
    - Downes, Agnes and Ralph (Box-folder 8/41)
    - Dox, Thurston (Box-folder 8/42)
    - D- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 8/43)
    - Effinger, Cecil, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 8/44)
    - Effinger, Cecil, 1946-1964, undated (Box-folder 8/45)
    - Engel, Carl (Box-folder 9/1)
    - E- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Farrar, Geraldine (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Fassett, James (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Fine, Irving Gifford (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Flanagan, William (Box-folder 9/6)
    - F- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Gaul, Harvey (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Glazer, David (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Goeb, Roger (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Gray, H. Willard (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Greissle, Felix (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Gutter, Robert (Box-folder 9/13)
    - G- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Haines, Edmund (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Hall, David (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Hamilton, Margaret (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Hanson, Howard (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Harmon, Carter (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Harris, Roy and Joanna (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Heinsheimer, Hans W. (Box-folder 9/21)
    - Hindemith, Paul, Letter from Ernest R. Voigt, P. Hindemith Personal Management, 1941 Sept. 26. (Box-folder 9/22)
    - Ho, Anita Magsaysay (Box-folder 9/23)
    - Hoiby, Lee (Box-folder 9/24)
    - Howe, Mary and Calderon (Box-folder 9/25)
    - Hull, Anne (Box-folder 9/26)
    - H- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Ísólfsson, Páll (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Jacobi, Frederick and Irene (Box-folder 9/29)
    - James, Philip (Box-folder 9/30)
    - Johnson, Thor (Box-folder 9/31)
    - Jones, Charles (Box-folder 9/32)
    - Josten, Werner, Correspondence from various members of the Josten family. (Box-folder 9/33)
    - J- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 9/34)
    - Kay, Ulysses (Box-folder 9/35)
    - Keller, Homer (Box-folder 9/36)
    - Kennan, Kent (Box-folder 9/37)
    - Kerr, Harrison (Box-folder 9/38)
    - Kindler, Hans (Box-folder 9/39)
    - Kochs, Ellis (Box-folder 9/40)
    - Korte, Karl (Box-folder 9/41)
    - Kramer, A. Walter (Box-folder 9/42)
    - Krenek, Ernst (Box-folder 9/43)
    - Kubik, Gail (Box-folder 10/1)
    - K- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Lewin-Richter Ossiander, Andres (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Lipkin, Arthur Bennett (Box-folder 10/4)
    - List, Eugene (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Luening, Otto (Box-folder 10/6)
    - L- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/7)
    - MacLeish, Archibald (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Mahler, Alma (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Malco, Nicolai (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Mayer, William (Box-folder 10/11)
    - McKay, George Frederick (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Menotti, Gian Carlo (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Meyers, Emerson (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Milhaud, Darius (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Mitchell, Marjorie (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Moeran, Ernest John (Box-folder 10/17)
    - Montgomery, John D. (Box-folder 10/18)
    - Moore, Douglas (Box-folder 10/19)
    - M- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/20)
    - Ormandy, Eugene (Box-folder 10/21)
    - O- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Palmer, Robert M. (Box-folder 10/23)
    - Parker, Horatio, Letters from Grace Semler. (Box-folder 10/24)
    - Parris, Robert (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Perry, Julia (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Pisk, Paul Amadeus (Box-folder 10/27)
    - Piston, Walter (Box-folder 10/28)
    - Pleasants, Henry and Virginia (Box-folder 10/29)
    - Porter, Quincy (Box-folder 10/30)
    - P-Q- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/31)
    - Rorem, Ned (Box-folder 10/32)
    - Rose, Hazel (Box-folder 10/33)
    - R- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/34)
    - Salmenhaara, Erkki (Box-folder 10/35)
    - Schein, Ann (Box-folder 10/36)
    - Schmedes, Dagmar (Box-folder 10/37)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold, Includes one letter from Schoenberg's attorney, Maurice Thorner. (Box-folder 10/38)
    - Schuman, William (Box-folder 10/39)
    - Sessions, Roger (Box-folder 10/40)
    - Smith, Russell (Box-folder 10/41)
    - Sowerby, Leo (Box-folder 10/42)
    - Spivacke, Harold (Box-folder 10/43)
    - Stahlman, Sylvia (Box-folder 10/44)
    - Stravinsky, Igor (Box-folder 10/45)
    - S- [miscellaneous] (Box-folder 10/46)
    - Taylor, Deems (Box-folder 10/47)
    - Taylor, Prentiss (Box-folder 10/48)
    - Thatcher, John S. (Box-folder 10/49)
    - Thompson, Randall (Box-folder 10/50)
    - Thomson, Virgil (Box-folder 10/51)
    - Thorne, Francis (Box-folder 10/52)
    - Tircuit, Heuwell (Box-folder 10/53)
    - Tournemire, Charles (Box-folder 10/54)
    - Turner, Charles (Box-folder 10/55)
    - T- [miscellanous] (Box-folder 10/56)
    - Wagenaar, Bernard (Box-folder 10/57)
    - Walton, William (Box-folder 10/58)
    - Warbure, Gerald F. (Box-folder 10/59)
    - Ward, Robert, 1942-1959 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Ward, Robert, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Ward, Robert, undated (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Watanabe, Akeo (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Watson, Frances (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Waxman, Donald (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Whithorne, Emerson (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Wilder, Alec (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Willan, Healey (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Williams, David McK (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Woodworth, G. Wallace (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Work, John W. (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Zallinger-Thurn, Maria von (Box-folder 11/13)
    - V-Z- [miscellaneous] and unidentified (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Letters by WRS (Box 11-13)
    - Castle, Margaret F., 1952-1953 (Box-folder 11/15)
    - Castle, Margaret F., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Castle, Margaret F., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Clark, Sidney and Eleanor, 1953-1963 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Clark, Sidney and Eleanor, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Clark, Sidney and Eleanor, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Clark, Sidney and Eleanor, 1969-1973, undated (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Davis, Louise, 1949 (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Davis, Louise, 1950 (Box-folder 11/23)
    - Davis, Louise, 1951 (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Davis, Louise, 1952 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Davis, Louise, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Davis, Louise, 1955 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Davis, Louise, 1956 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Davis, Louise, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Davis, Louise, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Davis, Louise, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Davis, Louise, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Davis, Louise, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Davis, Louise, 1967 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Davis, Louise, 1968 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Davis, Louise, 1969 (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Davis, Louise, 1970 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Davis, Louise, undated (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Howe, Mary (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Hull, Anne, 1958 (Box-folder 12/16)
    - Hull, Anne, 1959 (Box-folder 12/17)
    - Hull, Anne, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 12/18)
    - Hull, Anne, 1962 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Hull, Anne, 1963 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Hull, Anne, 1964 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Hull, Anne, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Moog, Robert (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Spivacke, Harold (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Strickland, Helen (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Waters, Ed (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13-14)
    - Gruenberg, Louis to H.W. Gray Publishing Co., Inc (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Letters about WRS by others (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Re: disposal of library, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Re: interviews regarding Barber, Cowell, Howe (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Re: miscellaneous employment, 1934-1966 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Re: miscellaneous recordings (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Re: research related to Schoenberg’s Variations for Organ, op. 40 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Re: WRS recording, An Electronic Trip to the Zoo (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Stokowski, Leopold to H.W. Gray Publishing Co., Inc. (Box-folder 14/5)
- Music (Box 15-19, OV 1)